# Thalita F. P. Dantas

• thalitafranciscoeelt@gmail.com • <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/thalitadataanalyst/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/thalitadataanalyst/</a> • <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/thalitadataanalyst/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/thalitadataanalyst/</

A Data Analyst with an engineering background and 3+ years of experience in EdTech, Fintech, and Energy. Led a team for 3 years, cutting project timelines by 50% through data analysis. Skilled in deriving insights from complex datasets to optimize business processes.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Analyst**

Matrix Energy - São Paulo, BR

Jul 2023 - PRESENT

- Streamlined and automated the updating process for executive reports, cutting the time needed by 67%.
- Proficient in data processing for insightful analysis, adept at crafting customized data visualizations for diverse sectors within energy company.
- Data governance leader developing data dictionaries, data models, and data flow diagrams.
- Provided support to junior staff, interns, and other learners across various departments in data analysis, utilizing effective communication, patience, empathy, and adaptability.

### **Data Analyst**

Cashme - São Paulo, BR

Sep 2021 - Jun2023

- Collaborated to achieve 200% increase in credit originations compared to the previous year by leveraging data to enhance operational aspects of the credit process with precise metrics.
- Analyzed KPIs across various company areas including Marketing, Finance, Sales, Human Resources, Technology, Data Quality, Profiles, and Customer Prospecting to support respective departments. Notably, the prospecting project witnessed a 3x increase in sales compared to the previous initiative.
- Introduced data governance techniques including data extraction, transformation, ETL processes Data Lake and Data Warehouse.

#### **Data Analyst**

Wiser Education - Curitiba, BR

Mar 2021 – Aug 2021

- $\bullet$  Collaborated with the call center control desks team to boost conversion rates by 10%, ensuring smooth operations.
- Developed user-friendly dashboards to analyze and improve the performance of customer service agents.
- $\bullet \textbf{Conducted data analysis and designed dashboards to effectively manage late payments and enhance customer recovery. } \\$

### **EDUCATION**

### Grad. School in Database and Business Intelligence, Feb 2021

Cruzeiro do Sul University - São Paulo, BR

### **B.Sc. in Industrial Engineering, Mar 2019**

Veiga de Almeida University - Rio de Janeiro, BR

## **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Business Intelligence Tools: Proficient in Power Bi, Tableau, Looker, and Metabase.
- **SQL:** Strong command of SQL (BigQuery, Snowflake, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MySQL).
- Python Proficiency: Familiarity with Python programming.
- ETL Tools: Experience with Alteryx and Apache Hop.
- CRM Systems: Knowledge of Salesforce and CRM Microsoft Dynamics.
- Communication: Skilled in English communication for meetings, technical texts, and emails.